<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computability on Virtual World</title>
    <link>http://virtworld.github.io/tags/computability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computability on Virtual World</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 20:54:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://virtworld.github.io/tags/computability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>G53COM Computability 可计算性 复习笔记</title>
      <link>http://virtworld.github.io/post/g53com-computability-1314-revision-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2014 20:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://virtworld.github.io/post/g53com-computability-1314-revision-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是一篇课程总结笔记，内容基于 G53COM 1314 年度的课件，讲师为 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.nott.ac.uk/~ajp/&#34;&gt;Dr Andrew Parkes&lt;/a&gt;。这篇文章&lt;strong&gt;并非&lt;/strong&gt;标准答案。 任何定义，解释和示例可能是不准确的或者错误的。请参考您自己的笔记。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-定义&#34;&gt;1. 定义&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;问题分类&#34;&gt;问题分类&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NC&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved in polylog time using polynomial a number of processors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DTIME(f(n))&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using some DTM in time f(n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P = U&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; DTIME(n&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using a DTM in any polynomial time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P-hard&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem X is said to be P-hard iff all problems within P can be reduced to X using polylog time on a polynomial number of processors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;P-complete&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem X is said to be P-complete iff it is in P and it is P-hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NTIME(f(n))&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using some NDTM in time f(n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NP = U&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; NTIME(n&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using some NDTM in any polynomial time. A language is accepted by a NDTM is a set of strings that there exists one or more than one execution path of NDTM that gives yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduction from X to Y&lt;/strong&gt;: convert any instance of X to some instance of Y.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NP-hard&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem X is said to be NP-hard iff any problem in NP can be reduced to X in polynomial time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NP-complete&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem X is sad to be NP-complete iff it’s in NP and it’s NP-hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DSPACE(f(n))&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using some DTM with space f(n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSPACE = U&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; DSPACE(n&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved by a DTM using polynomial space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSPACE-hard&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem X is said to be PSPACE-hard iff any problem in PSPACE can be reduced to X within polynomial time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSPACE-complete&lt;/strong&gt;: if a problem is PSPACE-complete if it is in PSPACE and it is PSPACE-hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NSPACE(f(n))&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using some NTDM with space f(n).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NPSPACE = U&lt;sub&gt;k&lt;/sub&gt; NSPACE(n&lt;sup&gt;k&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of problem that can be solved using a NTDM with polynomial space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>